Inventory of the Michael McFaul Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound recordings, 1991-2002 (Box 1-5)
  - Interviews of Russian political leaders and survey research groups' recordings, 1991-2002 (Box 3-5, Tape 63-170)
    - 'Svetlana,' NPO (nauchno-proizvodstvennoe ob"edinenie), 30 September 1992-12 October 1992 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0006677
      Part 1: Auctionering problems, Oct '92
      Part 2: Conversations with SV's managers 12.10.92
    - Tsypko, Aleksandr, 1995 July 19 (Box 5)
      These cassettes are effectively blank, as if the recorder was on during the interview, but the microphone was unplugged. - JS, 1 Apr 2013
    - Uss, Aleksandr (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0008325
    - Vasiliev, Dmitriĭ, 30 June 2002 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0009087
    - Yakovlev, 09 August 1995 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0006678
    - Yakunin, Gleb, 12 July 1995 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0009091
    - Yavlinskiĭ, Grigoriĭ, 1997 October 12 (Box 5)
      The cassette is effectively blank, as if the recorder was on during the interview, but the microphone was unplugged. - JS, 2 Apr 2013
    - Zaslavskiĭ, Il'ia, 14 July 1995 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0006683
    - Zavadskaia, 20 June 1995 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0009094
    - Zorkal’tsev, Viktor, 24 July 1995 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0009095
    - Zotov, N., 03 February 1991-02 March 1991 (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0006666
      Label reads: Int. - Zotov - lehcov 2-3-91
    - Unidentified (Box 5)
      Use copy reference number: 94039_a_0002377
      In Russian.
- Video recordings, 1996-2000 (Box 6)
  - "Cardiac Surgery Grand Rounds: Boris Yeltsin - the Heart of the Matter, Politics and Medicine,", 1996 (Folder 6: 1)
    1 VHS videocassette
  - ABC News Nightline on President Bill Clinton's visit to Russia, 2000 (Folder 6: 2)
  - "Capital Conversation: U.S. - Russia Relations," Belo Capital Bureau, 2000 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Survey research in Russia on federalism, political parties, and elections, 2000 (Folder 6: 4-22)
    3 VHS videocassettes and 16 VHS-C compact videocassettes
- Subject file, 1989-2001 (Box 7)
  - II Nezavisimyĭ zhenskiĭ forum, agenda and printed matter, 1992 (Folder 7: 1)
    Includes Fraktsiia politicheskogo dvizheniia "Zhenshchiny Rossii," bulletin, nos.1-4, 1994
  - Akademiia deputatskogo korpusa Rossii, 1990-1991 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Avgustovskii putch, 1991-1993 (Folder 7: 3)
    Includes Spektakl' nazyvalsia Putch, by Aleksandr Lebed', 1993
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1995-2001 (Folder 7: 4)
    Includes memoranda to members of the Russia-China project, 1996-2001
  - Defense industry conversion, 1992-2002 (Folder 7: 5-11)
    Includes "New Frontiers in U.S. - Russian Defense and Military Cooperation," Preventive Defense Project, briefing book, Washington D.C., 2002
  - Election campaign files, 1989-1999 (Folder 7-16)
    Printed matter, clippings, proclamations, leaflets, and notes relating to elections at state level
    - Soviet Union legislative election, 1989 (Folder 7: 12-13)
    - Parliamentary elections, 1993-1999 (Folder 8-15)
    - Presidential election, 1996 (Folder 16)
  - Gosudarstvennaia Duma files, 1889-1995 (Folder 17-19)
    Steno grams, reports, voting records, official documents, and brochures
  - Interlegal Research Center, 1991 (Folder 20: 1)
  - Labor movements, 1989-1995 (Folder 20: 2-8)
    Programs, reports, clippings, articles, and brochures
  - Mining independent trade union-Nezavisimy? profsoiuz gorniakov (NPG), 1990-1992 (Folder 20: 9-10)
    Appeals, leaflets, research material, meetings, memoranda, and clippings
  - Military reforms, 1991-1992 (Folder 20: 11-12)
    Clippings, and statements. Includes military bulletin "Postfactum"
  - Mossovet (city administration of Moscow), 1990-1992 (Folder 20: 13-15)
    Statements, minutes, election documents, clippings, reports, and printed matter
  - Mossovet (city administration of Moscow), 1990-1992 (Folder 21: 1-4)
    Statements, minutes, election documents, clippings, reports, and printed matter (contd.)
  - Parliamentary election campaign in Poland, Czech Republic, Romania, and Hungary, 1990-1992 (Folder 21: 5)
  - "Partinform," nezavisimoe agentstvo novosteĭ, 1992-1995 (Folder 21: 6-11)
  - "Partinform," nezavisimoe agentstvo novosteĭ (contd.), 1992-1995 (Folder 22: 1-3)
  - Political leaders, 1994-1995 (Folder 22: 4-9)
    Clippings, press releases, brochures. Includes "Factions" Assessment of Three Russian Policy Issues," sponsored by U.S. Department of State and The National Intelligence Council, March 1995
  - Political parties and movements, 1988-1995 (Folder 22: 10-13)
    Programs, statements, analytical articles, brochures, clippings, and notes
  - Political parties and movements, 1988-1995 (Folder 23-29)
    Programs, statements, analytical articles, brochures, clippings, and notes (contd.)
  - Privatization and legal development in Russia, 1990-1995 (Folder 30-34:)
    Analytical reports, parliament hearings' steno gram, agenda, articles, brochures, clippings, and notes
  - Privatization and legal development in Russia, 1990-1995 (Folder 35: 1-7)
    Analytical reports, parliament hearings' steno gram, agenda, articles, brochures, clippings, and notes (contd.)
  - Russian international affairs, 1993 (Folder 35: 8-9)
    Analytical reports and clippings
  - Samizdat bibliography, 1989-1990 (Folder 35: 10)
  - Sheĭnis, Viktor writings, 1997 (Folder 35: 11)
    See also box 5
  - Sociological surveys and political polls, 1994-1999 (Folder 36: 1-7)
    Includes "Rol' parlamenta v konstitutsionnoĭ reforme Rossii," round table, Moscow, 1996
  - "Strategiia" publications, 1994 (Folder 36: 8)
  - S"ezdy narodnykh deputatov RSFSR, 1990-1992 (Folder 36: 9-12)
    Participants' lists, speeches, statistics, clippings, and notes. Includes "Report on the Congress of Peoples Deputies Elections in the Russian Republic," by U.S. Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, March, 1990
  - Tamara Tselikovskaia trial, Tver', Russia, 1990 (Folder 37: 1)
  - Ukraine trade unions, 1989 (Folder 37: 2)
    Includes "Ukraine: Opinions and Perceptions Members of Independent Trade Unions," survey, 1999
  - Verkhovna Rada Ukraĭny, secretariat and bills, 1998-2001 (Folder 37: 3)
    Includes "Pro status kryms'kotatars'kogo narodu," 2000
  - "What the Papers Say," reviews, 1995 (Folder 37: 4-6)
- Printed matter, 1989-2001 (Box 38-60)
  Newspapers, journals, and brochures relating to election campaigns and other social, economic, and political conditions in Russia.
  - Brochures, bulletins, programs, leaflets, and journals, 1989-2001 (Folder 38-47)
  - Newspapers, 1989-2000 (Folder 48-60)
- Incremental Materials, 2000s (Box 61-67)
  Mainly includes materials relating to party politics in the Russian Federation during the early 2000s, in particular the Duma and presidential election campaigns of 2003-2004. There are files on various political parties, including ephemeral ones that existed only for the duration of the election cycle: leaflets, pamphlets, clippings and other printed matter, as well as limited circulation items such as the text of Anatolii Chubais’s famous “Russia as a Liberal Empire” speech of 25 September 2003.